<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Careers on Principal Economics</title>
    <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Careers on Principal Economics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 07:30:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.principaleconomics.com/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Careers</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/career/careers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/career/careers/</guid>
      <description>While we have no specific vacancies at present we are always keen to talk to interested candidates.
About you Preferably you have a first-class honours degree or higher qualification in Economics, Statistics, or related studies. We prioritise experienced candidates, with a minimum of five years relevant experience working in local or central government or consulting firms.
About us Principal Economics is an economic consultancy providing evidence-based decision support for public and private clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Senior) Economist position</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/career/economistposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 07:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/career/economistposition/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for one (senior) economist to join our team.
-Using principles of Economics to provide advice on a wide range of topical issues
-Working in an adhocracy and transparent organisational culture with supportive colleagues
-Wellington or Auckland location
About us Principal Economics is an economic consultancy providing evidence-based decision support for public and private clients. We have been working on a range of important topics around infrastructure, housing, social policy, climate change, and disruptive technologies (amongst other topics).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
