<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Team on Principal Economics</title>
    <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Team on Principal Economics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 11:52:18 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dr Eilya Torshizian</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/eilyatorshizian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 07:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/eilyatorshizian/</guid>
      <description>Eilya is the Director of Principal Economics. Before founding Principal Economics Eilya was a Principal Economist and the Head of Quantitative Analysis Team at New Zealand Institute of Economic Research (NZIER). Prior to that, when Auckland was in the middle of its recent housing crisis, Eilya was at the Chief Economist Unit of Auckland Council. Before that Eilya was lecturing at the University of Auckland. Before that Eilya was the CE of a mineral water manufacturing and was a partner at a holding company active in urban planning and construction, Information Technology and economic advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alina Fehling</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/alina-fehling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 07:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/alina-fehling/</guid>
      <description>Alina is an Economist at Principal Economics.
Alina is experienced in data analysis and is interested in welfare, inequality and trade topics. Before joining Principal Economics, Alina was a graduate economist at Capgemini in Berlin.
Alina is highly experienced in working with large datasets including time series and spatial data. Alina also assists in providing visualisations for Principal Economics clients. Alina is a Data Analyst with R (and the Shiny framework), and is specialised in ArcGIS and Stata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eugene Isack</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/eugeneisack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 07:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/eugeneisack/</guid>
      <description>Eugene is a Senior Economist at Principal Economics. Before joining Principal Economics Eugene was an Economist at New Zealand Institute of Economic Research (NZIER). Before that, Eugene was an Economist at Property Economics. Eugene has over 12-years’ experience in the economic industry, with substantial involvement both in public and private sector advisement.
Eugene is experienced in econometric modeler, with specialised skills in geographic information systems, big data analysis and is a registered Statistics IDI Researcher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Milad Maralani</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/miladmaralani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 07:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/team/miladmaralani/</guid>
      <description>Milad is a Senior Economist at Principal Economics. He is an applied economist with a strong background in understanding and modelling of how economic agents and sectors are linked and interact in response to programmes and policy changes. Before joining Principal Economics, Milad worked as an economist at the New Zealand Institute of Economic Research (NZIER) where he was responsible for CGE modelling of many in-place or proposed policies and investments in New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
