<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sectors on Principal Economics</title>
    <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sectors on Principal Economics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 11:52:18 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Economic impact of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/covid/</guid>
      <description>We assist with assessments of the impact of COVID-19 on demand for a range of services. Given the high level of uncertinty over how the outbreak evolves we provide guidance on how COVID-19 may affect your market given a range of potential scenarios.
Recent work: We assisted with Chorus&#39; submission to Commerce Commission to account for the impact of COVID-19 on the forecasts for the cost escalation series.
We use simulation methods, to estimate the likely impacts to capture the impacts of COVID-19 to provide estimates for our clients until published data is fully able capture the impact of the COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure and the economy</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>We assist our clients in identifying the benefits of primary and secondary impact of infrastructure investments
Productivity gains from timely investments lead to profitability of industries, which lead to higher wages, and higher demand in the economy, and increases in GDP and eventually higher intergenerational wellbeing for New Zealand communities. The impact of timely infrastructure investment on labour productivity may have been even more significant following the Covid-19 pandemic.
We provide the most comprehensive evidence-based framework for estimating the economic outcomes of infrastructure investment using the Principal Economics’ Computable General Equilibrium (CGE) model of the New Zealand and regional economies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population and demographic forecasting</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/population-demography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/population-demography/</guid>
      <description>Our population and demographic model provides decision support for the development of long term plans, transport modelling, public transport patronage and revenue forecasts, water infrastructure modelling and the development of asset management and infrastructure investment plans.
For population and employment forecasting we have developed Principal Economics’ Sub-regional Economic Activity Model (SEAM). SEAM is a stochastic microsimulation model developed to provide robust long-term forecasts for our clients.
Accounting for factors including:  Household composition (age, income) Employment and job locations Migration (inflows and outflows separately) The suburbs and regions are interconnected - we account for the spatial relationship (spill-overs) across suburbs Disaggregated relationships for different sectors: agriculture, other primary, manufacturing, wholesale, retail, accommodation and food services, transport, financial services, rental, professional, public, education, health, others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investments in the energy sector</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/energy/</guid>
      <description>We provide expert advice on areas of energy sector. Principal economics are experts in the field of energy economics with experience in developing and adopting economic models assessing energy issues in New Zealand.
We provide you a robust evidence-based framework for addressing energy related issues using the Principal Economics’ Computable General Equilibrium (CGE) model of the New Zealand and regional economies.
Our CGE model disaggregates power generation by fuel type (hydro, gas, geothermal, wind, other renewables), allowing us to answer your questions on how new policies or investments (including those related to climate change related programs) impact the energy and electricity sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Cost Benefit Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/scbaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/sectors/scbaf/</guid>
      <description>We developed the Social Cost Benefit Framework (SCBAF) for impact evaluation of individual interventions, with a focus on employment assistance (EA) programmes.
Our SCBAF framework provides a comprehensive and robust method for estimating the value of interventions, ensuring consistency of evaluation by making comparisons based on a common standard.
The aim of a CBA is to compare the gains of an activity from the costs of undertaking, and it can serve two particular purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
