<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Principal Economics</title>
    <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Principal Economics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 11:52:18 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cost benefit analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/cost-benefit-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/cost-benefit-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Making decisions in uncertain times needs precise understanding of the costs and benefits. We can assist by identifying fiscal, economic and wellbeing benefits from your investment decision or policy intervention.
The team at Principal Economics have the experience and credibility to undertake cost-benefit analysis for government and businesses on a wide range of issues. From developing tools and frameworks for Social Cost Benefit Analysis and undertaking Wider Economic Benefit Assessments for public sector clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting and modelling</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/forecasting-and-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/forecasting-and-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Principal Economics have developed a wide range of robust frontier economic evaluation frameworks to assist with your planning for future investments using best available data.
In partnership with international policy centres, academics, and local experts, Principal Economics provides the right solution for credible assessments of policies and investments. We have an efficient and experienced team who have provided advice on a wide range of topics and have extensive background in the industry and at academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic impact analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/economic-impact-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/economic-impact-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Estimate the impact of your activities using our extensive economic assessment frameworks
We provide independant economic impact analysis to evaluate the impacts a project, program or policy on regions, demographic groups, industry or the wider economy. Our team are experienced in communicating complicated economic issues to audiences with different backgrounds and familiar with political sensitivity of regional investments.
To provide a comprehensive understanding of the impact economic activties, we provide a robust methodology that captures the impact on all sectors of the economy and across all regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic research</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/economic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/economic-research/</guid>
      <description>We offer independent review of highly sensitive and technically complex issues.
The team at Principal Economics have been involved in a wide range of critical policy and analytical analyses, including development of cost benefit analysis framework development, distributional effect analysis, literature review and policy assessment.
We prioritise studies with the highest quality well implemented research designs in our assessments and colloborate with international policy centres, academics, and local experts to provide the best quality research for your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/market-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/market-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Our team of economists help you to understand the demand for your services/products within the wider market. Principal Economics provides insight to the trend of the market and how your investment affect economic outcomes, including labour markets, economic productvity.
Principal Economics combine our multidisplanary expertise, sector knowledge and frontier solutions to provide sensible advice based on an understanding of your business, empirics, and risks.
We provide a wide range of robust assessments frameworks, accounting for cultural, economic, environmental, and social outcomes of investments/interventions across different fields, including but exclusive to urban development, regeneration, transport, infrastructure investment and labour market activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial analysis and modelling</title>
      <link>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/spatial-analysis-and-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.principaleconomics.com/services/spatial-analysis-and-modelling/</guid>
      <description>We help you to understand the relationships between your investment/intervention and the activities of businesses and households in neighbouring areas.
Our team at Principal Economics encompass a unique combination of knowledge, experience, and skills suited for solving spatial and urban economic problems.We are have extensive experience in economic modelling with specialised skills in geographic information systems (GIS). Providing solutions to our clients across a range of urban economic issues including those related to the residential housing market, infrastructure development, and public transport.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
